<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter>
  <title>mLaw Edoc (Electronic Document) Concepts</title>

  <section>
    <title>Introduction</title>

    <para>Each action that creates or edits data in mLaw is represented by an
    electronic document (edoc). Such an actions are creating or editing a
    conveyance, a court case, or a contract, assigning or editing a court
    case, conveyance or contract assignment, creating or editing a conveyance
    type etc.</para>

    <para> An edoc has a preset workflow that is aligned to the approval
    levels in the organization. An edoc also posses a state - that changes
    when the user takes actions on it. Each document has the following
    information:</para>

    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Initiator</emphasis></para>

        <para>This is the person who has initiated the action.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Actions</emphasis></para>

        <para>These are:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Submit - forwards the information to the next person in the
            workflow or commits the changes if there is no further approval
            needed.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Cancel - Cancels the edo. Any changes made will be
            lost.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Save - Saves the edoc so that it can be worked on at a later
            date. Saved documents can be retrieved from the action list or
            edoc search. Notifications may also be generated for saved
            documents depending on the user's configuration.</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Status</emphasis></para>

        <para>Once an document is created it has the status 'initiated'. When
        it is saved, it has the status 'saved'. If an initiated edoc is closed
        before it is saved, any changes are lost and cannot be recovered. The
        initiator clicks the 'submit' button to forward it to the next stage
        of the workflow if it exists. An edoc that needs further approval will
        have a status of enroute and will appear on the action list of the
        person/people who need to attend to it. An edoc that has no further
        approval stage in the workflow will have a status of 'final' once it
        is submitted.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">eDoc number</emphasis></para>

        <para>This is a unique number that is assigned to each document and is
        incremental</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">The creation time</emphasis></para>

        <para>The time the document was initiated</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Description</emphasis></para>

        <para>This describes in summary, the circumstances sorrounding the
        action being taken e.g. 'New conveyance for client James', 'adding
        terms of service', 'Steve Vs John'</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Explanation</emphasis></para>

        <para>This a more detailed description of the circumstances e.g. 'as
        agreed in the board meeting on 07 Sept 2012 where it was suggested by
        Director Peter and seconded by Director Paul'</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Notes and Attachments</emphasis></para>

        <para>This section allows the attachment of relevant files e.g. copies
        of certificates, certificates of search, scanned identification
        documents etc.</para>
      </listitem>

      <listitem>
        <para><emphasis role="bold">Route log</emphasis></para>

        <para>It contains information as to the actions that have been taken
        on the document starting from the initiator to the present. It also
        links the actions of the users to the state of the document at
        specific times.</para>

        <para/>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>

    <section>
      <title>Edoc Search</title>

      <para>This is accessible on the main menu by clicking the 'doc search'
      menu or using the direct links in the shortcuts page. Using doc search,
      it is possible to locate documents based on their type, the initiator
      and the date created.</para>

      <section>
        <title>Action List</title>

        <para>The action list is where edocs pending action are displayed.
        This applies to documents that have been saved by the user. When a
        user has been specified as an approver in a workflow, the submitted
        documents also appear on the action list in addition to receiving an
        email notification. The action list shows the type of document, the
        status, the action requested, edoc number among other details.</para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
